[ Cheering ]
[ 欢呼 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 上午好
My name is Bruce Nilo.
我是 Bruce Nilo
I'm one of the engineering
我是 UIKit 的
managers for UIKit.
一名工程经理
And today we're going to be
今天我们将讨论
discussing a new feature you
一项新的特性
might've heard that we're
你可能已经听说过
introducing in iOS 11.
它将被引入到 iOS 11中
This is going to be the first of
这是四场专题会议中的第一场
four dedicated sessions where
在这四场会议期间
we're going to explore the
我们将专门探索
breadth and depth of the new
新的拖放 API 的
drag-and-drop APIs.
广度和深度
We're going to show you just how
我们会向你展示
easy it is using these APIs to
用这些 API 将拖放
add drag and drop to your app in
嵌入到你的 App 中非常简单
ways that your users are going
你的用户也会
to love.
爱上这项功能
We're going to start by talking
我们首先会谈到
about the goals and concepts
拖放背后的
behind drag and drop.
目标和概念
We're going to go deep into some
我们还会深入下去
of the core APIs that you're
谈谈将拖放加入到
going to need to add drag and
你的 App 中所需要的
drop to your apps.
核心 API
And then, we're going to follow
之后我们会有
that up with a demonstration
一个实例演示
showing just how easy they are
看一下这些 API 有多么
to use.
简单易用
Finally, we're going to wrap up
最后我们会提出一些建议
with some suggestions about what
提示你如何
you can do to quickly adopt this
快速使用这项出色的
great, new feature.
新特性
So what is drag and drop?
那什么是拖放呢
I think we all know that it's a
我想我们都知道
way to graphically move data
就是以图形方式把数据
from one application to another
从一个应用程序移动到另一个
or even within the same
应用程序 或者在应用程序内部
application.
移动的操作
When we set about designing drag
当我们开始设计拖放
and drop and bringing it to iOS,
并将其引入 iOS 时
we had some goals in mind.
我们想实现这些目标
We wanted it to be fast and
我们希望它快速并能
responsive.
迅速响应
In particular, we didn't want to
我们尤其不希望
move or copy data that we didn't
移动或拷贝不需要的
need to.
数据
Therefore, we leveraged the
因此我们充分利用了
capabilities of the new file
iOS 11 中新文件系统
system on iOS 11 and we made our
的功能 设计了自己的
APIs, we structured our APIs in
API  我们使这些 API
a way such that we never move
只有在请求数据时
data unless it's requested.
才会移动数据
And moreover, they're designed
此外在这样的设计中
to deliver the data to your
数据以异步方式
applications asynchronously so
传送到你的应用程序中
your apps never block the run
这样你的 App 就不会阻止 run loop
loop and prevent your users from
不会阻止用户做他们
doing what they want to do.
想做的操作
We also wanted drag and drop to
我们还希望确保拖放的
be secure in a way that the
安全性 要高于
pasteboard isn't.
粘贴板
In particular, data is only
尤其要保证数据只能
visible to the destination
对目的应用程序
application that your user
也就是用户希望
indicates they want to drop
放置数据的应用程序
over.
可见
But that's not all.
但这还不够
We wanted our source
我们希望源应用程序
applications to have the ability
有能力将
to restrict access to their data
获取其数据的权限
to just their app, to other apps
限制在 App 本身或者
developed by the same team, and
同一团队开发的其他 App 之间
then, of course, to all apps on
当然也向系统中所有其他 App
the system.
开放
And when we GM, we will also be
在发布 GM 版本时我们也会
supporting manage configuration
支持企业用户的
for our enterprise customers.
管理配置
So finally, the most important
最后最重要的就是
thing was that it be a great
需要为用户提供
Multi-Touch experience.
Multi-Touch 的体验
And to do this, it was clear we
为做到这一点很明显
were going to have to reimagine
我们需要在很多
drag and drop in many important
重要方面对拖放提出
ways.
新的设想
So let's take a look at some
那么来看一下
aspect of that experience we had
我们设想中这一体验的
in mind.
几个方面
And before I start this video,
在播放视频之前
let me give you some context.
我先介绍下背景
I recently took some pictures of
我这几天拍了几张
the Empire State Building in New
纽约帝国大厦的照片
York, and in this video, you're
下面的视频中你会
going to see me use a bunch of
看到我用几个
different fingers to compose an
不同的手指来完成一封邮件
email to some friends.
发给朋友们
We're going to start off in
我们从 Spotlight 开始
Spotlight, where we're going to
这里我们先拖拽一个链接
drag a link, swipe up the doc,
向上滑出 Dock
hover over the Safari icon to
悬停在 Safari 图标上
launch it, and drop that link
启动 Safari 把链接放在
onto the + button to open up a
+ 按钮上打开一个
tab in Safari.
标签页
We're then going to select some
然后选择一些文本
text, long press, and begin to
长按开始移动
move and realize that wasn't
不过发现那并不是我
really the text I wanted at all.
想要的文本
I can easily cancel the drag,
我可以轻松取消拖动
select the text that I care
然后选择我
about.
想要的文本
And again, the gesture is a long
手势仍然是长按
press where the text lifts up,
文本会抬起
followed by a move, at which
接着是移动这时
point I can interact with the
我可以和系统的其他部分
rest of the system.
进行交互
I can open the Split so that I
我可以打开 Split View  这样就能
can better see the photos that I
更好地看到我需要的照片
care about, and now I can select
现在我可以选择
a number of the Empire State
多张帝国大厦的
Building photos.
照片
You'll notice that I'm still
你会注意到我还在
dragging the text with my other
用另一只手拖拽着
hand and I'm adding photos to my
文本而用右手
right.
添加图像
I'm going to hand that
我将选择的照片
collection of photos to my left
交给左手
hand so I can better swipe mail
以便将邮件划到
into the right split.
右半屏
I'm going to pass it over to my
再把照片交给右手
right hand again so that I can
这样就可以把它们
drop them into the mail Compose
放置到邮箱的编写
sheet.
区域
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So that's what we mean by a
这就是我们所说的
great Multi-Touch experience.
优秀的 Multi-Touch 体验
What did we see?
我们看到了什么
The interface is alive.
交互界面是即时呈现的
It's deeply integrated with all
它深度融合进了
of iOS.
iOS 之中
You can drag out of Spotlight.
你可以从 Spotlight 中拖拽
You can bring up the doc.
可以划出 Dock
Indeed, the system UI is
实际上系统 UI
implemented on top of drag and
是基于拖放
drop.
实现的
There's great visual feedback,
视觉反馈优秀
fantastic animations.
动画效果出众
You can hover over controls to
你可以在控件上悬停
navigate.
进行导航
You can add items to an existing
你可以添加项目到已有的
drag session.
拖拽会话
You can transfer drags between
你可以在不同手指
your fingers, between your
以及两手之间转移拖拽
hands, and you can even start
甚至可以同时开始
multiple drag sessions at once.
多个拖拽会话
So before we get into some of
在讨论其中的一些
the concepts, let me talk about
概念之前我想先说说
drag and drop on the iPhone.
iPhone 上的拖放
We initially envisioned drag and
起初我们将拖放预想为
drop as an iPad productivity
iPad 的生产效率
feature.
特性
However, all of the APIs are in
但事实上所有这些 API
fact available on the phone.
在手机上也是可用的
There is one restriction, and
但有一项限制
that is on the phone, we only
就是在 iPhone 上
allow drags to execute within
我们只允许拖拽在同一个
the same application.
应用程序中执行
So let's turn our attention to
那我们来看看其中的
some of the key concepts.
一些关键概念
These are going to provide a
这些概念将提供良好基础
great basis for understanding
帮助理解
the APIs that follow.
之后会讲到的 API
So we're going to talk about the
我们先来谈谈
phases of a drag session.
拖拽会话的各个阶段
We break a drag session into
我们将一个拖拽会话
four of them, in which both the
分解成四个阶段
source application and the
这其中源应用程序
destination application have a
和目的应用程序
part to play.
都会参与
And it all begins with the lift.
整个过程从内容抬起开始
In the lift, that's when you
抬起 就是
long press, and the view lifts
长按以使视图
out of the screen.
离开屏幕的过程
When, and then, when the user
然后当用户
begins to drag, you enter the
开始拖拽时就进入了
drag phase.
拖拽阶段
In the drag phase, you can
这一阶段你可以
update the previews of what the
在拖拽的同时
things look like as you're
更新所拖拽内容
dragging.
外观的预览
You can tap to add.
你可以点击以添加内容
You can hover to navigate.
可以悬停以进行导航
When the user lifts their
当用户抬起手指时
finger, one of two things can
会有两种
happen.
可能的情况
Either the drag is canceled or
或者是拖拽取消
you actually want those items
或者是用户想在
dropped where the user lifted
抬起手指的位置
their finger.
放置内容
We provide great targeting APIs
我们提供很棒的针对性 API
to make those set-down
让放置动画
animations look fantastic.
效果不俗
And finally, we enter the data
最后我们进入数据转移阶段
transfer phase, and that's the
在这一阶段
phase where the destination
目的应用程序
application requests the data
会向源应用程序
from the source.
请求数据
So before we go into the
在讨论拖拽 API 的
building blocks of the drag
构成之前
APIs, let me take a moment to
我想告诉大家
say that it's all built around a
这都是围绕着交互
concept called an interaction.
这一概念构建的
An interaction is a really
交互是一个非常
simple concept.
简单的概念
It's basically takes an input
基本上就是接收输入
and generates an effect of some
并产生某种
sort.
效果
The drag-and-drop APIs are built
拖放 API 围绕这一概念构建
around this for a couple of
有以下几个
reasons.
原因
One is, is it lets us to provide
第一它让我们在系统中
a consistent look and feel for
为拖放提供
drag and drop across the system.
一致的观感
But most importantly, it makes
但最重要的是
it really easy for you to add
能让你可以非常轻松地
drag and drop to your app
把拖拽加入到你的 App 中
without having to rearrange your
而不需要重新整理代码
code or your view hierarchies.
或视图层次体系
So let me introduce the drag
我来介绍下拖拽
interaction.
交互
It's attached to a view, and as
它属于一个视图
you heard in the, perhaps in the
可能你在之前演讲中
previous talk, it's very similar
听说过它很像一个
to a gesture recognizer.
手势识别器
If you've ever used them, the
使用过的人会发现
pattern is the same.
模式是一样的
You create an object with a
你用委托（delegate）创建一个对象
delegate, and it is via the
通过这个委托
delegate that you interact with
你可以与系统进行
the system.
交互
So for example, the delegate is
比如可以让委托
asked to return the drag items
在抬起动画开始前
just before the lift animation
返回拖拽的
happens.
项目
This is the one required method
这就是针对拖拽交互委托
for a drag interaction delegate.
所必需的方法
The delegate is free to return
委托可以没有
no items whatsoever -- in which
返回项 这种情况下
case, the gesture will fail and
手势无效
the touch will be processed as
点按会按照
normal.
正常情况处理
OK, so what's a drag item?
那什么是拖拽项呢
Well, the drag item is really
拖拽项正是
the whole point of it all.
其中的关键所在
It's the model object that's
它是一个模型对象
associated with the view that
与拖拽交互所属的视图
the interaction is attached to.
相关联
Drag item for drag and drop
在拖放功能中 拖拽项
embodies both what the items
既包括其在屏幕上
look like as they're moved
移动时的外观
around the screen, the preview,
也就是预览
as well as a promise by the
也包括当目的应用程序
source application to deliver
请求数据时 源应用程序
the data to the destination when
向其传输数据的
it requests.
承诺（promise）
We call these promises item
我们称这些承诺为
providers, and they're
Item Provider（项目提供器）在 iOS11 中
implemented in iOS 11 by some
它们由 NSItemProvider 中的
new additions to NSItemProvider.
一些新增内容执行
So how do you enable a drop?
那么 如何实现放置
It's easy.
很简单
The first way to do it is to
第一种方法是
take advantage of a new property
利用 UIResponder 中增加的
that we added to UIResponder
一项新属性
called paste configuration.
叫做 Paste Configuration（粘贴配置）
What is a paste configuration?
什么是粘贴配置呢
Basically, it's a declarative
大致来说它是一种声明式的
way of specifying the types that
方法来指定 UIResponder
your responder can either accept
可以接收为
as a paste or as a drop.
粘贴或置放的类
To take advantage of paste
要利用粘贴配置
configurations, you need to
你需要
implement a new method called
实现一种新方法叫做
paste itemProviders.
paste itemProviders
And if you do, you will be able
实现后就可以
to support paste and drag and,
无需额外配置 使用
and drop out of the box.
粘贴和放置
However, for more sophisticated
但是对于更复杂的
drop interactions, you're going
放置交互你需要
to want to add a drop
在视图中添加一个
interaction to your view.
放置交互
And you do so in a very similar
用类似添加拖拽交互
way that you add a drag
的方法就可以
interaction.
添加放置交互
And when you do, when you are
这样操作之后
dragging over a view that has
当拖拽到包含这种交互
such an interaction, we're going
的视图上时我们会
to query that delegate to tell
对委托发起查询让它
us whether or not it's
告诉我们是否对
interested in the items that are
拖拽到它上面的
actually being dragged over it.
项目感兴趣
And it will reply with and
委托会做出回应
intention or a proposal, as we
我们称之为意图
call it.
或者建议
Now, on touch up, the delegate
抬起手指时委托可能说
might've said, not interested.
不感兴趣
In which case, the drag will be
这时拖拽会取消
canceled and all those previews
所有的预览
are going to animate back to
将通过动画 回到他们
whence they came and, or off the
原来的位置或者从屏幕上
screen to indicate that it was
消失以表示
canceled.
拖拽取消
However, the more interesting
然而更有意思的是
bit is when the delegate says,
当委托说
yeah, I'm interested in those
是的我对这些项目
items.
有兴趣 的时候
In which case, the system is
这时系统会
going to say, perform the drop.
下令执行放置
And it is within the scope of
就在这个回调函数的
this callback and it is only
作用域内
within the scope of this
也只有在这个作用域内
callback that the delegate can
委托才能
request the items that it's
请求它感兴趣的
interested in.
项目
Or more precisely, the
更确切地说是
representations of the items.
项目的 Representation（描述）
And once, when it does so, at
一旦发出请求
that point, the source
此时源应用程序
application will fulfill its
就会履行承诺
promise and the system will
并且系统会
deliver that data back to the
以异步方式将数据
destination app asynchronously.
传输回目的应用程序
OK, there's a lot more to
好的要探讨的
discuss.
还有很多
For example, what's the life
比如从目的应用程序或者
cycle of a drag session from the
源应用程序的角度看
perspective of the destination
拖拽会话的的生命周期
or the source?
是什么样的
How do you make your set-down
怎么能让放置的过渡效果
transitions look great?
看上去很棒
What do you do if the data
该如何处理
transfer takes a long time to
数据传输用时过长
complete?
的问题
Before we answer some of these
回答部分问题之前
questions, it's going to help to
看一下这张图会
look at this picture because
有所帮助因为
it's going to give you a good
它会以鸟瞰图的方式
bird's-eye view of how our API
让你看到我们的 API
is structured.
是如何构建的
On the left in blue, you're
左边蓝色部分
going to see those objects and
可以看到一些对象和类
classes that the source
源应用程序
application is going to use to
将使用它们实现
realize a drag.
拖拽
And on the right, what the
右边部分是
destination application uses to
目的应用程序用来
realize a drop.
实现放置的对象和类
And in the middle are those
中间部分的
objects and classes that both
对象和类
the source and the destination
源应用和目的应用都会
use to fulfill the contract of
用到以完成拖放
drag and drop.
契约
Now, to discuss these
现在要探讨
foundational classes in more
这些基本类更多的细节
detail, I'm going to bring Kurt
我将请上我的同事
Revis, my colleague, up on the
Kurt Revis
stage.
上台
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Bruce.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢  Bruce
So Bruce gave you the big
刚才  Bruce 介绍了拖放的
picture of drag and drop.
整体情况
Now, I'm going to tell you more
我会向大家介绍更多
about using the drag-and-drop
使用拖放API
API.
的方法
So I'll talk about three things.
我会谈及三个方面
I'll give you a timeline about
我会介绍进行拖放时
what happens during drag and
事件的时间线
drop, I'll introduce you to
我会介绍
these essential API methods that
API 中一些最核心的方法
you need to implement to get
你需要执行这些方法
drag and drop working in your
才能在你的 App 中实现拖放
app, and then finally, I'll
最后 我会
introduce you to the full API.
介绍完整的 API
So drag and drop looks pretty
拖放看上去十分简单
simple, right?
对吗
There's an object on the screen.
屏幕上有个对象
The users touches it.
用户点按它
It lifts up.
它会抬起
Then, they move it around inside
然后用户在 App 内部移动它
that app, maybe over to a
也可能移动到
different app.
另外一个 App
Finally, they release their
最终用户松开
touch.
手指
The touch ends.
按压停止
The object drops down into its
对象被放置到
new position.
新的位置
Of course, there's a lot more
当然这背后的情况
going on underneath, so let's
更为复杂 那我们来说说
talk about what happens when.
何时发生何事
It all starts when a touch comes
一切都从点按
down on a view that has a drag
含有拖拽交互的视图
interaction.
开始
UIKit sets up this lift
UIKit 会创建
animation, and then as that
抬起的动画随后由于
touch stays down, we run that
点按动作持续 我们
lift all the way to its
会完整运行抬起的动画
completion.
直至动画结束
Then, when the user moves their
然后用户手指移动
finger far enough, we start the
达到一定距离时我们会真正
drag in earnest.
启动拖拽
The object lifts up over
该对象抬起呈现于
everything else in the view and
视图中其他内容之上以及
over all apps, and the user can
所有 App 之上用户可以
drag it around on the screen.
在屏幕上随意拖动
Finally, at some point, the user
最后 在某个位置
is going to release their touch,
用户会松开手指
and what we do depends on where
我们的操作则取决于
that was.
这个位置
The first possibility is that
第一种可能是
the view underneath is not
下面的视图
interested in accepting the
没有兴趣接收
drop.
放置
In that case, we run a short
此时我们会运行一小段
cancellation animation.
取消动画
Stepping back, maybe the
退一步看可能
location was on a view that
这个位置的视图
wanted to accept the drop.
希望接收放置
In that case, there's more to
那么就有更多的事情
do.
要做
We ask the delegate of the drop
我们让放置交互的委托
interaction to perform the drop,
执行放置
to request the data, and then
请求数据然后
two things happen in parallel.
有两件事会同步发生
We run the drop animations to
我们会播放放置动画
animate those things into their
让拖拽的内容动起来
final positions, and we do the
到达最终位置并进行
data transfer.
数据传输
So those two boxes are the same
这两个框大小一样
size, but really, that data
但实际上
transfer is asynchronous and
数据传输是异步的
nobody knows how long it's going
谁也不能提前预知
to take ahead of time.
需要多久完成
It might be very quick.
可能会 [口误]
It might, excuse me, it might be
抱歉可能会
very quick.
很快
In fact, it might be faster than
实际上也许比放置动画
those drop animations.
要快一些
Or it could take substantially
也可能会需要
longer -- for instance, if the
更长的时间比如
data needs to be downloaded.
需要下载数据
Now, you've seen this whole
现在大家看完了完整的
timeline.
时间线
That's everything that can
这就是所有可能
happen.
发生的情况
UIKit's responsible for running
UIKit 负责运行
this timeline, but we need your
这个时间线但在三个特定
help at three specific places.
节点上需要你们的帮助
The first one is when the drag
第一个就是拖拽
starts.
开始的时候
We need to find the items to be
我们需要找到要拖拽
dragged.
的项目
We do that by calling this
我们会调用
required method on the drag
拖拽交互委托上必需的方法
interaction delegate,
也就是
dragInteraction
dragInteraction
itemsForBeginning session.
itemsForBeginning session
You return us an array of drag
这会给我们返回一个包含
items.
拖拽项的数组
I'll give an example here.
我举个例子
We're going to drag just a
我们只拖拽一个
single string, so my object will
字符串那么对象就是
be the string "Hello World."
Hello World 这个字符串
I put this inside of an
我把它放进
NSItemProvider.
NSItemProvider
This is the data representation,
这是数据表达
data transfer level of things.
数据传输层面的东西
Now, note that I'm casting this
现在注意我把它转换成
to an NSString.
NSString
This is because NSItemProvider
这是因为 NSItemProvider
only deals with objects.
只处理对象
It doesn't deal with Swift
不处理 Swift
struct.
结构体
Next, I make a drag item.
接下来我创建一个拖拽项
I go up to the drag-and-drop
这上升到了
level.
拖放层面
So I make a UIDragItem with that
我用项目提供器创建
item provider.
UIDragItem
And finally, I just return that
最后返回那一个项目
single item.
即可
The new API essential is on the
下一项 API 的核心方法在
drop side.
放置端
Now, while you're dragging that
当你在屏幕上
object around on the screen,
拖拽对象时
UIKit wants to know at every
UIKit 在每个点上都想知道
point, what would happen if the
如果用户此时在此处
user lifted their finger right
抬起手指
here and now?
会发生什么
You tell us that by implementing
这是通过放置交互委托上
this method on the drop
的这个方法
interaction delegate,
实现的
dropInteraction
也就是 dropInteraction
sessionDidUpdate, and you return
sessionDidUpdate  这会返回
a drop proposal.
置放建议
So this is called when we enter
当我们进入这个视图
your view and then also when it
并在当前视图内移动对象时
moves around inside of your view
就会实现这个方法
every time you can return a new
每次你都可以返回
proposal.
新的建议
You make a UIDropProposal and
通过 UIDropProposal 和
use a drop operation to do that.
放置操作就可以做到
Now, a drop operation is an
放置操作是一种
enum.
枚举
There's four possible values.
有四种可能的值
I'll talk about these in order
我会按照可能性
from most likely to least
由大到小的顺序
likely.
来谈
The first one's cancel.
首先是 .cancel
This is saying that when the
就是说当用户
user lifts their finger, I don't
抬起手指时
want to accept the drag.
不接受拖拽
Just cancel the drag.
而是取消拖拽
Second is copy.
第二是 .copy
This is the opposite.
这正好相反
You're saying, I do want that
这意味着 确实要得到
data.
那份数据
I will accept that data and copy
希望接收该数据并把它
it into the view that the user
拷贝到用户放置的
is dropping on.
视图中去
Most of the time, this is what
大多数情况下应该给出
you should propose.
上面两种建议
In general, on iOS, drag and
总体来说在 iOS 上拖放
drop copies from one place to
会将数据从一处拷贝到
another.
另一处
The next one is move.
下一个是 .move
This is a lot like copy, but
这很像拷贝
you're indicating that you want
但却表示你希望
the data to be moved from the
将数据从源应用程序
source to the destination.
移动到目的应用程序
This is a bit more complicated,
这更复杂一些
and you should know that UIKit
你应该知道 UIKit
can't make it look like a move
无法使它看上去
for you.
像一次移动
We just give you the data the
我们给出数据的方式
exact same way as with a copy.
和拷贝时完全一样
Your delegates need to cooperate
你的委托需要配合
in order to make it look like a
才能让它看上去像
move.
移动
So this is only allowed within a
所以这只有在同一款 App 内
single app.
才能进行
Your drag interaction delegate
你的拖拽交互委托必须
must allow it.
同意才可以
There's a delegate method where
有一个委托方法
we'll ask if it does allow it.
询问委托是否同意
And the drag interaction should
拖拽交互会
check this property on the drop
检查 UIDropSession 的
session allowsMoveOperation.
allowsMoveOperation 属性
If that's true, then you can
如果值为真那么你就可以
propose the move operation.
建议移动操作
Next, the forbidden operation.
下一个是 .forbidden
This is just like cancel, except
这个很像 .cancel
that we show this additional
但我们会在拖拽项上增加
badge on the drag item.
一个标志
This is telling the user that
这是为了告诉用户
although normally you could drop
正常情况下你可以
here, in this specific case, you
在此放置 但在此情况下
can't.
不可以
For instance, if I was dragging
例如如果我把一张图像
an image over a folder, normally
拖拽到文件夹上
that would be allowed, but if
正常情况下是可以的但如果
that folder was read only, then
文件夹是只读的
I would use the forbidden badge
就会用禁止标志
to tell the user that it can't
告诉用户现在不能执行
happen right now.
这个操作
So this is a bit forbidding, so
这会让人觉得反感
don't use it all the time.
所以不要经常使用
Use it sparingly.
要谨慎使用
The next API essential, the
下面是第三个 API 核心操作
third one, you proposed an
之前你已经提议了
operation earlier.
一项操作
Now, if it's a copy or move, you
如果是拷贝或者移动的话
need to perform that operation.
你需要执行这一操作
So on the drop delegate, drop
那么在放置
interaction delegate, you
交互委托上你需要
implement dropInteraction
实现 dropInteraction
performDrop.
performDrop
And here's your chance to load
这里 就可以从会话中
data from the session.
加载数据
In fact, this is the only place
实际上也只有这里
you can do that.
可以加载数据
So I'll show two examples of
我来举两个例子
loading data from the items in
演示从会话中的项目
the session.
加载数据
The first one is a simple one.
第一个很简单
We'll use a convenience method
我们使用会话中一项
on the session called session
很便捷的方法叫做
loadObjectsofClass.
session.loadObjects(ofClass)
Here I'm using UIImage.
这里我用的是 UIImage
I call this, and I provide a
我调用它并且提供了
closure to be called back later
一个闭包在那些对象
on when those objects are
可用时可以
available.
回调这个闭包
When they come in, I can iterate
对象进入闭包时我可以对列表
through that list.
进行迭代
I know they will be UIImages, so
我知道他们会是 UIImage 所以
it's okay to do this force cast
这里进行强行转换
here.
没有问题
And then, I can update my UI
然后就可以直接
directly.
更新 UI
So here I'm changing the image
这里我在 imageView 内
inside of an imageView.
更换图像
So this convenience method calls
这个便捷的方法会把我回调
me back on the main queue.
到主队列
I can update my UI right there
我直接就可以
and then.
更新 UI
Here's a more complex example.
下面是一个更复杂的例子
I'm going to iterate through the
我将对会话中的多个
items, the UI drag items inside
UI 拖拽项
of my session.
进行迭代
I could do different things for
需要的话我可以对不同的项
different ones if I wanted to.
进行不同的操作
I, now, I'll take, for an item,
现在我要对其中一项
I will use the NSItemProvider,
使用 NSItemProvider 这是
the lower-level API for loading
用来加载对象的
objects.
底层 API
So I'll load an object of a
我会加载一个类中的
class.
一个对象
Again, UIImage.
仍然是 UIImage
You see that my closure gets two
可以看到闭包获得了
things now.
两项内容
It gets an object and it also
有一个对象还有一个
gets this error object.
错误对象
The other thing about this is
还有另外一件事情是
that it's lower level.
它位于底层
This calls me back on a
把我回调到
background queue.
后台队列
So if I had more processing to
所以如果我需要对数据
do of the data, I could do it
做更多的处理就可以
right there and then.
在此时此地直接进行处理
But also, it's my responsibility
但当需要更新
to dispatch back to the main
UI 的时候我也要
queue when it's time to update
负责调度回
my UI.
主队列
So of course, dispatch back to
那就回到
Handle that error.
来纠正差错
So that was the three API
这就是三个 API 核心方法
essentials: getting the objects
获取拖拽对象
to drag, getting a drag
获得拖拽建议
proposal, and then actually
然后实际执行
performing the drop.
放置
Now, we'll cycle back all the
现在我们再回过头
way to the beginning of this
回到时间线的起点
timeline again and talk about
来谈谈
all the other delegate methods
其他的委托方法
because there's a lot more.
因为还有很多
First, I'm going to talk about
首先我会从
it from the point of view of the
拖拽交互委托
drag interaction delegate.
的角度来谈
So immediately after you
一旦提供图像
provided those images, those
作为拖拽项
items to drag, if you don't
如果你不进行
implement anything else, we will
其他操作 我们只会
just lift up your entire view.
把整个视图抬起
So the drag image, the preview
所以拖动图像 也就是预览
will be a snapshot of your
会是整个视图的
entire view.
一个快照
If that is not what you want,
如果这不是你想要的
you can customize that preview.
你可以自定义预览
So implement drag interaction
利用 dragInteraction() 的
previewForLifting item and
previewForLifting 项可以
return a targeted drag preview.
返回 UITargetedDragPreview
I'll explain what this means
我用一个例子
with an example.
来说明
Targeted drag preview has really
UITargetedDragPreview
two parts to it.
包含两部分
There's the drag preview part
分别是拖拽预览部分
and the target part.
和目标部分
The drag preview part is just
拖拽预览部分规定了
saying, what does the item look
拖拽时项目
like while it's being dragged?
所呈现的样子
And you tell us that by
要告诉我们这一点
providing us a view.
你需要提供一个视图
So in this case, I'm making an
这种情况下我会创建
image view containing an image
imageView  包括一幅
from my asset catalog.
来自 Asset Catalog 的图像
That automatically gets sized
它会根据图像大小
based on that image.
自动调节尺寸
That's what my thing will look
那就是它将呈现的
like.
样子
The second part is the target
第二部分是
part.
目标部分
Now, you'll note that that's a
你会发现这是一个独立的
freestanding view.
视图
It's not in the view hierarchy
不存在于 View Hierarchy
anywhere.
（视图层次结构）中
So UIKit doesn't know where to
所以 UIKit 不知道在哪
show it.
显示它
You need to tell us with a
你需要用目标
target.
告诉我们
A target is two things: It's a
目标有两方面含义
containing view and it's a
它既是一个容器视图
location within that view.
也是容器视图内的一个位置
So here from my containing view,
在这个容器视图中
I'm going to use the
我会使用
interactions view.
交互视图
This is where the drag is
这是拖拽开始的
starting.
地方
And for the location, I'll use
对于位置我会使用
these sessions location in the
视图中的
view.
会话位置
This is where the user's finger
这是用户手指的
is.
位置
I take those two things, I put
我把这两项内容
them together into a drag
一起放入
preview target, and then
拖拽预览目标
finally, I make a
最后我会创建
UITargetedDragPreview with that
UITargetedDragPreview 这会用到
view, with a default set of
上面的视图一套默认参数
parameters, and with that
以及上面的
target.
目标
That's the lift.
以上是抬起部分
The other thing you can do
抬起阶段你还可以做的
during the lift phase is animate
一件事情是同时让你自己的 UI
your own UI alongside the lift.
动起来
So maybe you've got other UI
可能在视图内
inside of your view that needs
有其他 UI 需要
to be dimmed out during a drag.
在拖拽期间暗淡下来
Something like that.
诸如此类的效果
You can implement this method --
你可以实现这个方法
drag interaction will animate
也就是 dragInteraction 的
lift with an animator -- and use
willAnimate 方法
that animator to add animations
同时 调用 animator 的
alongside.
addAnimations
Here I'm just changing the
这里我只改变了
background color of a view.
视图的背景色
You can also get the completion
你还可以得到抬起动画的
of that lift animation.
结束态
Now, note that, with the lift,
现在注意对于抬起
there's two ways that it can
可以有两种结束
end.
方式
If the user holds down their
如果用户在抬起过程中
finger long enough through the
一直按压时间足够长
whole lift, we'll go all the way
那就会完整
to the end.
进行这个过程
The position will be end.
此时的位置就是终点
If the user lifts their finger
如果用户中途
partway through the lift, we'll
抬起手指
run it in reverse all the way
我们则会将动画反过来
back to the beginning and we'll
一直回到开头并且
tell you the position is start.
告诉你 此时的位置是起点
As that session begins after the
因为用户移动手指后
user moves their finger, we'll
会话开始
tell you the session will begin.
我们会告诉你会话即将开始
We will then ask you some
我们会问几个
questions.
问题
For instance, we'll ask you,
比如我们会问
does this session allow the move
这个会话允许 .move
operation?
操作吗
And then, as that session moves
然后随着会话的移动
around, we'll tell you every
每移动一次我们都会
time it moves.
告诉你
So you can find out the new
所以你可以在这里找到
location there.
新的位置
Also, during this drag phase,
同时在这个拖拽阶段
you can add items to the
你可以在拖放会话中
drag-and-drop session.
增加项目
So I've got one touch that's
这里有一个点按操作
moving that drag around.
用于移动拖拽
Another touch can come down and
另一个点按操作可以去点击
tap on any view that has a drag
任何含有拖拽交互的
interaction.
视窗
It can, it doesn't have to be
不一定非要是
the original view.
原始视窗
It could be a completely
可以是完全不同的
different view.
视窗
When we detect this tap, we will
检测到点击后
ask the delegate for items to
我们会向委托请求项目
add to the session.
加入到会话中
You do that by implementing drag
在一个点上点击调用
interaction items for adding to
dragInteraction 的 itemsForAddingTo session
session with a touch at a point.
就可以做到这一点
So you can hit Test using that
你可以用这个点进行 Hit-test
point, find out what items, if
弄清楚有没有任何
any, that you want to add to the
项目要添加到
session.
会话中
If you've got some, return them.
如果找到了就返回这些项目
If you don't have anything to
如果没有
add, just return an empty array,
就返回一个空数组
and then we will pass that touch
然后我们会像
along just like we normally
正常情况一样
would have.
把触摸传递下去
And of course, you can customize
当然你可以自定义
what the preview of those items
那些项目的预览
looks like.
样式
Finally, when the session ends,
最后会话结束时
the user releases their finger.
用户松开手指
We'll tell you the session will
我们会告诉你会话将
end with the operation that was
以所选的操作
chosen.
结束
And if it's ending in a cancel,
如果以取消结束
there's a cancellation
会有一个结束动画
animation, which you can
动画可以进行
customize.
自定义
So implement drag interaction
那么用默认值调用
previewForCancelling item with a
dragInteraction previewForCancelling item
default and return a targeted
就会返回
drag preview.
UITargetedDragPreview
You can return nil here, and the
这里你可以返回空
item will just disappear in
项目就会
place.
就地消失
You can use our default one and
你可以用系统默认值
change its target.
并改变它的目标
So if you know where that thing
如果你知道它
should fly back to, all you have
该飞回到哪里的话你就只需要
to do is give it a new target.
给它一个新目标
It will fly right back there.
它就会飞回到那儿
You can animate alongside the
你可以用和以前一样的方式
cancellation animation the same
和取消动画一起增加
way as before.
动画
Finally, when we're done, we'll
最终完成后我们会
tell you that the session did
告诉你会话
end.
结束了
If it was a copy or a move,
如果是拷贝或者移动
there's no cancellation
是没有取消动画的
animation, so we just tell you
那么我们会告诉你
the session did end and we also
会话结束了我们还会
tell you when the data transfer
在数据传输完成时
is finished.
通知你
So that was the drag interaction
以上是拖拽交互
side.
一侧
Now, let's talk about the drop
现在我们聊聊置放交互
interaction side.
这一端
This is a little more
这个要更为
interesting.
有趣
There's only one drag
要开始拖拽
interaction that's involved in
只涉及到一个
starting that drag.
拖拽交互
But it can go over lots of
但它可以经过很多
different views, and they can
不同的视图这些视图可以
all have their own drop
有它们自己的置放交互
interaction with the same
可以与同一个委托进行交互
delegate or multiple delegates.
也可以与多个委托进行交互
But in the end, only one of them
但最终它们中只有一个
gets to choose what happens when
能够选择用户抬起手指后
the user lifts their finger.
的动作
So when that drag-and-drop
所以当拖拽会话
session enters your view, you've
进入到你的视图你已经有了
got a drop interaction.
一个置放交互
The first thing we'll do is ask
我们首先要做的是问你
you, can you handle that
你能处理
session?
该会话吗
So we implement, you can
那么你可以
implement this method, drop
调用这个方法
interaction canHandle session.
也就是 dropInteraction canHandle session
And you can't check what data is
你不能查看实际被拖拽的是
actually being dragged.
什么数据
We don't give you access to that
我们还没提供这个权限
yet, but you can find the types
但是你可以找到
of data that are being dragged.
被拖拽数据的类型
So let's say you're only
那么假设你只对
interested in images.
图像感兴趣
You can check session
你可以查看
canLoadObjectsofClass UIImage.
canLoadObjectsofClass UIImage 会话
Or you can do something more
或者你可以做更
specific.
具体的事情
If you're interested in specific
如果你对特定的
uniform type identifiers, you
统一类型标识符感兴趣
can check if any items in that
你可以查看会话中有没有项目
session conform to that specific
符合那个特定的
uniform type identifier.
统一类型标识符
So here I'm using image PNG, if
那这里我就用 PNG 图像
I was only interested in PNG
假设我只对 PNG 格式的
images.
图像感兴趣
Next, after you've said that you
接下来在你说可以
can handle the drag session,
处理该拖拽会话后
we'll tell you when that session
我们会在会话
enters your view, we'll tell you
进入你的视图时
when it moves around inside of
和在你的视图内移动时
your view -- of course, you
通知你当然你会
return a proposal there -- and
返回一个建议 我们
we'll tell you when it exits.
会在它存在时通知你
And these can of course happen
当然这些可以发生多次
multiple times -- enter, exit,
进入退出
Also, while the session is
另外会话进行过程中
happening, springloading might
可能发生
happen.
Spring-loading（弹跳加载）
So we have built-in support in
所以我们在 UIKit 中
UIKit for springloading.
内置了对弹跳加载的支持
Several different classes, such
有不同的类比如
as UIButton.
UIButton
All you have to do is say,
你所需要做的就是给出
isSpringLoaded equals true.
isSpringLoaded = true
When that drag-and-drop session
当拖拽会话
hovers over that button, the
悬浮在那个按钮上时
button's action will
按钮的动作会
automatically run.
自动运行
Or you can set up your own
或者你可以建立自己的
springloaded interaction with
弹跳加载交互
its own handler to be called
当需要激活时调用其自身的
when it's time to activate and
处理器即可并把它
add that to any view you like.
添加到任何你要的视图
Finally, when the session ends
最后当会话在
on the dropInteraction delegate,
dropInteraction 委托上结束时
we'll tell you the session did
我们会告诉你
end.
会话结束
So every interaction, every drop
所以见到过这个会话的
interaction that has ever seen
每个交互每个放置交互
this session will be told that
都会被告知
it's ending.
会话结束
If you were keeping track of it,
如果你正在跟踪会话
now you can stop keeping track
现在就可以停止
of it.
跟踪了
If there's a drop to perform, of
当然如果需要执行放置
course, there's more to do.
那就有更多需要做的
We talked about the perform
我们已经说过
phase.
执行阶段了
Now, let's talk about the
现在我们说说
animations and the data
动画和数据
transfer.
传输
The animations are exactly the
动画方面放置动画
same for drop animations as they
和取消动画
were for cancellation
的动画部分
animations.
是完全一样的
Just the API names are
只是 API 的名称
different.
有所不同
So now, it's on the drop
那现在它在 dropInteraction 委托上的
interaction delegate preview for
previewForDropping item
dropping item, but you can do
但你可以做
exactly the same things.
完全相同的事情
You can animate alongside the
用同样的方法
same way.
让它动起来
And finally, when all those drop
最终所有项目的
animations of all the items are
所有放置动画完成时
done, we'll tell you conclude
我们会告诉你结束
drop.
放置
For the data transfer, of
当然在数据传输上
course, this closure gets called
当数据可用时
when that data's available.
这个闭包会被调用
But something I didn't mention
但我刚才没有提到的一点是
earlier: When you start the load
当你开始加载数据时
of the data, you can get a
你会得到一个
progress object, and this
Progress（进度）对象
progress object can tell you how
这个对象可以告诉你
much of the data transfer is
数据传输已完成多少
done, is it finished yet, and
是否已经结束
you can even cancel the data
你甚至可以在这里
transfer from there.
取消数据传输
Also, you can get those progress
此外你可以为每个项
objects per item, or there's a
创建一个进度对象
progress object on the entire
或者可以有一个整个
session that wraps up all the
会话的进度对象可以
progress of all the item
结束所有加载项的
loading.
进度
And there you have it.
就是这些
That's the full timeline of drag
以上就是拖放的完整
and drop.
时间线
That's everything that can
所有会发生的情况
happen.
都在这里
You know about these three
你了解了三个 API 的核心函数
essential API functions that you
你需要实现它们
should implement to get drag and
才可以实现
drop working.
拖放
And I hope you got the real
这里我真正希望你们
message here, which is
理解的一点是
customizing drag and drop is
拖放的自定义是通过
done through these interaction
这些交互委托
delegates.
实现的
That's how UIKit and your app
这就是 UIKit 和你的 App
work together to make a
是如何一同工作
fantastic drag-and-drop
来实现优秀的拖放
experience.
体验的
I'll hand you over to Emmanuel,
我要邀请 Emanuele 上台
who will show you how to add
向大家展示如何给 App
drag and drop to an app.
添加拖放
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Kurt.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Kurt
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Using drag-and-drop
&gt;&gt; 我们利用拖放交互
interactions, we created
为图像创造了
skeuomorphic pinboard for
一个拟物化的
images.
记事板
So we can start a drag from
比如我们可以
photos, for example.
从图像拖拽开始
We can bring it over the
可以把它拖到
pinboard.
记事板上
And when we drop it, we'll copy
放置时就可以拷贝
the image and show it in the
图像 并显示在
pinboard.
记事板上
Notice the drop animation scales
注意 放置动画
down the image and, when we
按比例缩小了图像
receive the data in the
而我们在记事板中
pinboard, will show the full
收到数据时动画会显示
image.
完整的图像
We can also drag it on the
我们也可以把它拖到
pinboard and see that we're
记事板上可以看到
going to dim the original image.
原始图像会变暗
And we can also drag that back
还可以把它拖拽
into photos to add it.
添加回照片 App 中
Hopefully.
希望如此
Yeah, that's -- this used to
嗯这个以前
work.
是可以的
[laughs] We can also drag it in
[笑声] 还可以在同一个记事板中
the same pinboard, and then when
拖拽图像然后当我们
we drop it, we will just
放置时就会重新
rearrange it.
排列
And see, look again at the
再看一下
animation.
动画
We dimmed the original image,
先让原图变暗
and when we drop it, we hide the
当放置时就把原图像隐藏
original image, and then we show
然后我们在新的位置
it in the new spot.
显示图像
So let's switch back to the code
那我们回来看看代码
and see how this is implemented.
看看这是如何实现的
So we start in our main view
我们从主视图控制器开始
controller by adding a drop
在视图中添加一个放置交互
interaction and a drag
和一个
interaction to our view.
拖拽交互
And then, we're going to set the
然后将视图控制器设为
view controller as the delegate
这些交互的
of those interactions.
委托
Then, we're going to implement a
然后我们要实现
few drop interaction delegate
几个放置交互委托的
methods.
方法
The first one is drop
第一个是
interaction can handle session,
dropInteraction 的 canHandle 会话
and this will return true if the
如果会话可以加载图像
session can load images.
就会返回 true
It's very simple.
很简单
The second one is drop
第二个是
interaction sessionDidUpdate,
dropInteraction 的 sessionDidUpdate
and here we return a proposal
这里我们返回一个建议
where we specify what kind of
指定想要执行的
operation we want to perform.
是哪种操作
So we have two cases.
有两种情况
The first one is if the drag
第一种是如果拖拽
started in another application,
来自其他应用程序
we want to perform a copy
我们希望执行
operation.
拷贝操作
And we can check that by looking
我们可以通过查看
at the session localDragSession
session.localDragSession 这一属性
property.
进行检查
So if it's new, it means that
如果属性为空意味着
the operation, that the drag was
这一拖拽操作
started in another application
源自另一个应用程序
and we're going to do a copy.
那我们会进行拷贝
Otherwise, we are just
否则我们只是
rearranging the item and we're
重新排列项目
going to do a move operation.
会进行一次移动操作
Third, we're going to implement
第三我们会实现
dropInteraction performDrop
dropInteraction performDrop
session.
会话
Again, we only want to copy the
同样如果拖拽源自其他应用程序
data if the drag started in
我们就只希望拷贝
another application.
数据
So again, we do this check if
所以 我们会再次检查
the local drag session is new.
localDragSession 是否为空
And then, we're going to perform
然后我们会先执行放置
the drop first by getting the
方法是通过调用
drop point of where the user
session.location(in: .view)
lifted the finger by calling
得到用户抬起手指的
session location in view.
那个放置点
And then, we are going to go
然后我们会检查
over each drag item in the
会话中的每个拖拽项
session and call a helper
并调用帮助函数
function that will load the
它会从项目提供器中
image from the item provider,
加载图像
put it in an image view, and
放入图像视图
then display it in the pinboard
然后利用刚才的那个点
using that center point that we
将其显示在
got.
记事板中
We also want to perform a drop
我们还想在抬起手指时
animation when we release the
执行一个
finger.
放置动画
So again, we have two cases.
仍然会有两种情况
In drop interaction
在 dropInteraction 的
previewForDropping item, we want
previewForDropping item 中
to return a preview that scales
我们希望返回一个预览
down when the drag comes from
如果拖拽来自其他应用程序
another application.
预览会缩小
And otherwise, if we're moving
并且如果我们
the image from the pinboard, we
从记事板移动图像
are not going to apply any
就不会应用任何
effects.
效果
We're just going to drop it in
只会把它就地
place.
放置
So we can check if the item is
因此我们可以检查 该项目
coming from a local drag or from
是来自本地拖拽还是
an external drag by checking
外部拖拽方法是查看
this property on drag item,
拖拽项的这个叫做
which is called localObject.
localObject 的属性
And if the item is coming from
如果项目来自
another application, then we
其他应用程序我们会返回
return nil.
空值
And this will have the effect
这就会有我们之前
that we saw before.
看到的效果
Just will scale down the
也就是缩小预览
preview, and then it will stay
并且 预览会停留在
in place.
原地
The default preview instead will
而默认预览则会
scale down and move to the
缩小并移动到
center of the pinboard, but
记事板中心
that's not what we want.
但这不是我们想要的
In the case we're moving an
当我们从记事板
image from the pinboard, so
移动图像
we're just rearranging it, we're
以重新排列时
going to animate it in place.
我们会让它就地动起来
So to get that, we need to
为此我们需要
retarget the default preview.
为默认预览重新指定目标
And as Kurt explained, we need a
如 Kurt 介绍的那样我们需要
container, which is the pinboard
一个容器就是记事板本身
itself, and the center in that
还需要视图的中心
view, which is the center of the
也就是预览的
preview.
中心
And then, we're just going to
然后我们将
retarget the default preview and
为默认预览重新指定目标 并
return that.
把它返回
Next, we're going to implement
接下来我们要实现
drop interaction
dropInteraction 的
willAnimateDropwith animator.
willAnimateDropwithanimator
Here we want to animate a local
这里我们要使本地移动产生动画
move because, as you've seen
因为就像你之前看到的
before, we had dimmed out the
我们使原图像
original image view, and when we
视图变暗当把它
drop it into a new place, we're
置放在新的地方
going to hide the previous, the
我们会把原来位置上的
image in the previous location
图像隐藏
and then show it again at the
然后在动画结束时
end of the animation into the
在新的位置
new spot.
显示图像
So we're going to add an
我们会添加一个
alongside animation and we're
伴随动画并将
going to fade the drag item to
拖拽项透明度逐渐降低至
alpha equals 0.
alpha=0
And then, at the end of the
接下来在动画末尾
animation, so by adding a
通过添加一个
completion block, we're going to
Completion Block（完成块）我们可以设置
set the new center of that image
该图像视图的新中心
view, and then we're going to
然后通过设置其alpha值为1
show it back by setting its
我们可以让它重新
alpha to 1.
显示出来
And here you can see that we're
这里你可以看到
again checking a local object.
我们再次检查了本地对象
In this case, I'm passing an
这种情况下我会传递
index so that I know where in my
一个索引以便知晓
model object the image is, and
图像在模型对象中的位置
we're going to see in a moment
我们一会就可以看到
in the drag interaction how to
在拖拽交互中如何
set that up.
设置
So I'll go into the drag
那我下面就谈谈
interaction delegate.
拖拽交互委托
I have to implement, first of
首先我需要实现的是
all, what kind of data I want to
在拖拽中要传递的
pass in the drag.
是哪种数据
And I installed the interaction
我在整个记事板上
on the whole pinboard.
安装了交互
So what I want to do is give the
那我想做的是
image that is under my finger.
给出我手指下方的图像
So to do that, I first need to
为此我首先需要
get the touch of the drag by
得到拖拽的点按这可以通过
calling again session location
再次调用 session.location(in: .view)
in view.
实现
And then, if there is an image
然后如果手指下方
under my finger, I want to get
有图像我要获得图像
the image, the data for that
以及图像的数据
image, wrap it into an item
将数据打包到
provider, wrap the item provider
项目提供器再把项目提供器
in a drag item, and then attach
打包进 dragItem（拖拽项）然后附上
that additional information that
其他信息这些信息将允许我
will allow me in the drop site
在置放点识别出
to recognize that local drag
那个本地
item.
拖拽项
Next, we need to provide a
下面我们需要为该项目
preview for that item.
提供一个预览
So we said before, if we don't
如前所述如果我们
provide a preview, the drag
不提供预览拖拽交互
interaction by default will take
会默认为整个视图
a snapshot of the whole view.
获取快照
And we clearly don't want to do
很明显我们不希望
that.
那样
We just want to provide a
我们只希望为
preview for the single image
正在拖拽的单张图像
that we're dragging.
提供预览
So we do that by getting the
做到这一点需要通过获取
index of the drag item, we get
拖拽项的目录
its associated image view, and
获取它相关的图像视图
then we pass that as a targeted
然后作为目标预览
preview.
传递
Finally, we want to dim out the
最后拖拽一旦开始
original image view once we
我们就会让原始图像
start the drag.
变暗
So we're going to add a
所以 我们要添加
completion block to this drag
一个完成块
interaction animator pass in a
到拖拽交互的 animator 中
willAnimateLift delegate.
在 willAnimateLift 委托中传递
And so we're going to add the
那我们添加这个
completion block, and the lift
完成块抬起就结束了
ended, so if the position is
如果位置是终点
end, then we're going to fade
那就使原始项颜色
the original item to alpha 0.5.
减淡至 alpha 值为 0.5
And that's really it.
这就是全部了
So you've seen how simple it is
大家已经看到了
to add drag-and-drop
添加拖放交互有多
interactions.
简单
This example also contains, also
这个例子也展示了
shows how to implement a
如何实现
[inaudible] configuration that
Pace Configuration
you can use together with your
Pace Configuration 可以和你的放置交互
drop interaction, and the sample
一起使用示例代码
code will be available online,
网上可以找到
so make sure to check it out.
大家一定要去看一下
Back to Bruce.
交回给 Bruce
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Emman.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢  Emanuele
&gt;&gt; Okay, so by now, you guys are
&gt;&gt; 好的 现在你们已经等不及
just going to run back to your
跑到自己的笔记本电脑上
laptops -- I see you already
我看有人已经带进来了
have them -- and add drag and
给你们的 App 添加
drop to your apps.
拖放了
And so I'm going to just share a
那么现在我要分享
couple of words of advice about
几条建议是关于如何
how to expedite that process.
让这个过程更加顺利的
First of all, don't do that
首先不要立马
right away.
开始操作
Explore the system.
先探索下系统
See what we've done.
看看我们都做了什么
See the types of set-down
看看我们实现的
animations that we have
放置动画的种类有哪些
implemented and the types of
以及我们实际传输的
data that we actually transfer.
那些数据类型
I think you'll be surprised.
我相信你会感到惊讶的
And then, go simple.
然后从简单的开始
Try to add a drop target, maybe
试着添加一个放置目标
using a pace configuration, and
可以用 Pace Configuration 来做
just kind of get a feel for how
只是感受一下它是如何
it works.
工作的
Experiment with a drag source.
用拖拽源实验一下
And even try to springload a
甚至尝试弹跳加载一两个
control or two.
控件
And then, you're going to look
然后你会看着它说
at it and say, it just doesn't
就是有哪里
look right.
看上去不对
What are we missing?
我们漏掉了什么呢
And that's when you're going to
这时 你就需要
have to dive a little bit deeper
更深入地研究
into these drag-and-drop APIs
这些拖放 API 了
because there's a lot of them.
因为有很多这样的 API
And we've made this easy for
我们也让这个过程
you.
足够简单了
And so I'm going to refer back
所以我要重新回到
to this picture again, and I'm
这张图开始
just going to start out.
谈一谈
There is a talk on mastering the
后面会有一场关于精通
drag-and-drop APIs, which is
这些拖放 API 的演讲
going to go even deeper into
它会更加深入
them than what Kurt gave you an
比 Kurt 的大致讲解
overview of.
更详细
There's going to be a session on
还会有一场会议是关于
what we've done with
我们如何改进
NSItemProvider, and you're going
NSItemProvider 的这场会议
to find it fascinating.
也会很精彩
We can drag and drop files, for
比如我们可以拖放文件
example, that you can open in
你可以就地打开这些文件
place, and you can actually
实际上你可以
provision the data from your
利用文件提供器
source using a file provider.
从你的源代码中提供数据
And we're going to go into that
我们会在那场演讲中
in detail in that talk.
深入讲解
There's a bit more.
还有更多的内容
For example, text view has a
比如文本视图有一个委托
delegate, a higher-level
是一个较高层的
delegate for supporting drag and
委托 支持
drop.
拖放
So if you have custom
所以如果你有自定义的附件
attachments or want some kind of
或者需要某种
custom text processing, you
自定义文本处理
should explore the APIs on those
你应该探究下这些委托上的
delegates.
API
And I know many of you have
我知道你们中的很多人
table views and collection views
在 App 中使用表格视图
in your apps, and if you want
和集合视图如果你们想
them to support drag and drop,
让这些视图支持拖放
we've created some great
我们也开发了一些非常棒的
higher-level APIs, and there's
高层 API
an entire talk dedicated to that
会有一整场的演讲都是关于
topic which you should really go
这个话题你们真的应该
see.
去看看
As usual, there's a lot more
和往常一样这个链接里
information about this talk in
有关于这场演讲
particular along with the sample
的更多信息
app at this link.
尤其是有示例 App
Here are some of the related
这里是一些相关的
sessions.
会议
I added one about the file
我增加了一个关于
provider enhancements as well as
文件提供器改进的会议
how you can, one on Spotlight,
以及一场关于 Spotlight 的会议
which'll talk about how you can
它会谈及你怎么样可以
actually drag and drop items
拖放 Spotlight 为
that your, that Spotlight finds
你的 App 找到的
for your app.
项目
If you have any questions,
如果你有任何问题
please drop by.
请来找我们
And I hope you guys have a great
希望你们能享受
WWDC.
WWDC
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]